<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" >
  <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator>
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" />
  <updated>2020-10-09T17:36:59+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://localhost:4000/</id>

  
    <title type="html">Angeleene (Zemmy) S. Ang</title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Aspiring Physicist. Perpetually curious. Tries to be a bit of everything. Possibly secretly a starchy tuber.</subtitle>
  

  

  
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Photonic Hook under pulsed Illumination</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2020/05/13/pulsed-pnj/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photonic Hook under pulsed Illumination" />
      <published>2020-05-13T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2020-05-13T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/research/2020/05/13/pulsed-pnj</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2020/05/13/pulsed-pnj/"></content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html"></summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Atomic Trapping using all-dielectric waveguides</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2019/05/31/waveguide-atom-trap/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Atomic Trapping using all-dielectric waveguides" />
      <published>2019-05-31T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2019-05-31T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/research/2019/05/31/waveguide-atom-trap</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2019/05/31/waveguide-atom-trap/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;calculated the electric fields generated by the proposed nano-atenna/waveguide system using Lumerical FDTD and a batch script.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;performed post-processing on the results using several Matlab scripts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;created the illustrations for the paper in Blender, and 3D animations for use in presentations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;worked with colleagues in the Physics Department of BGU to analyze the results. wrote and edited the manuscript, summarized the available related literature.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;presented the results of the research in multiple conferences: oral presentation and 2 posters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">calculated the electric fields generated by the proposed nano-atenna/waveguide system using Lumerical FDTD and a batch script. performed post-processing on the results using several Matlab scripts created the illustrations for the paper in Blender, and 3D animations for use in presentations worked with colleagues in the Physics Department of BGU to analyze the results. wrote and edited the manuscript, summarized the available related literature. presented the results of the research in multiple conferences: oral presentation and 2 posters</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">zemmyang.github.io</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/05/01/zaghio/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="zemmyang.github.io" />
      <published>2019-05-01T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2019-05-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/05/01/zaghio</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/05/01/zaghio/">&lt;p&gt;Using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jeromelachaud/freelancer-theme&quot;&gt;Freelancer theme by jeromelachaud&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeromelachaud.com/freelancer-theme/&quot;&gt;also here&lt;/a&gt;, I extended the features to include support for multiple sets of projects, a timeline (as seen in the Education section), and changed the colors a bit.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="projects" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Using the Freelancer theme by jeromelachaud, also here, I extended the features to include support for multiple sets of projects, a timeline (as seen in the Education section), and changed the colors a bit.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Photonic Hook Optical Manipulator</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2018/02/01/photonic-hook/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Photonic Hook Optical Manipulator" />
      <published>2018-02-01T00:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2018-02-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/research/2018/02/01/photonic-hook</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2018/02/01/photonic-hook/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;simulated the asymmetric dielectric microstructure in &lt;strong&gt;Comsol 5.2&lt;/strong&gt; using the &lt;em&gt;Electromagnetic Waves Frequency Domain&lt;/em&gt; solver&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;post-processed part of the results using &lt;strong&gt;Matlab&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;performed a review of related literature on photonic jets and their capability to trap nanoparticles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wrote the initial draft of the manuscript, revised the text according to the instructions of my co-authors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;created the 3D model of the photonic hook shown in Fig 1 of the publication using the field data from Comsol, as well as the force and field plots in the paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;made a 3D animation of an approximation of the behavior of the calculated movement of the nanoparticles under the electric field, for presentation purposes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;presented the results of the publication in two conferences: France (oral, invited talk) and Israel (poster).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">simulated the asymmetric dielectric microstructure in Comsol 5.2 using the Electromagnetic Waves Frequency Domain solver post-processed part of the results using Matlab performed a review of related literature on photonic jets and their capability to trap nanoparticles wrote the initial draft of the manuscript, revised the text according to the instructions of my co-authors created the 3D model of the photonic hook shown in Fig 1 of the publication using the field data from Comsol, as well as the force and field plots in the paper. made a 3D animation of an approximation of the behavior of the calculated movement of the nanoparticles under the electric field, for presentation purposes. presented the results of the publication in two conferences: France (oral, invited talk) and Israel (poster).</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">PhD in Electro-optical Engineering</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/education/2017/10/01/phd-electrooptics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="PhD in Electro-optical Engineering" />
      <published>2017-10-01T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2017-10-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/education/2017/10/01/phd-electrooptics</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/education/2017/10/01/phd-electrooptics/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;notable-courses-taken&quot;&gt;Notable courses taken&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrated Photonics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Imaging Principles and Optical Imaging Systems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="education" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Notable courses taken</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">MSc Photonics and Optical Information Technologies</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/education/2017/07/01/ms-photonics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="MSc Photonics and Optical Information Technologies" />
      <published>2017-07-01T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2017-07-01T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/education/2017/07/01/ms-photonics</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/education/2017/07/01/ms-photonics/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;official-university-description&quot;&gt;Official University description&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The master program (120 ECTS) gives deep knowledge in fundamental physics and provides hands-on experience in laboratory work, technology, and numerical simulations, which are essential for industry or academy career. The study programs cover the fundamentals of electrodynamics, quantum mechanics, and solid-state physics. The wide range of special courses delivered by young researchers includes up to date courses in nanophotonics, quantum optics, numerical methods, radiophysics, and others. The program involves intensive laboratory studies with the facilities of the centre: optical and radiofrequency instrumentation, laser writing technique, nanotechnology fabrication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;notable-courses-taken&quot;&gt;Notable courses taken&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Computer Simulations in Physics (instruction in Python)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nanoplasmonics and Photophysics of Intensive Light Exposure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Radiophysics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quantum Optics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="education" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Official University description</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Scattering Forces from Photonic Crystals</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2017/01/23/phc-scattering-forces/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Scattering Forces from Photonic Crystals" />
      <published>2017-01-23T00:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2017-01-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/research/2017/01/23/phc-scattering-forces</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2017/01/23/phc-scattering-forces/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;find other periodic nanostructures in literature that can generate negative refraction, scale them to the appropriate wavelength, and simulate the field propagation using &lt;strong&gt;Comsol 5.1&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;calculated the optical forces generated within these structures, and compare the results with what is expected according to mathematical analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wrote part of the manuscript, detailing the results and documenting the method used in the research. generated the plots used in the paper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;collaborated with a remote supervisor in Florida, USA, while being based in St. Petersburg.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;presented the results of the publication at two conferences (poster and oral) in Russia.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">find other periodic nanostructures in literature that can generate negative refraction, scale them to the appropriate wavelength, and simulate the field propagation using Comsol 5.1. calculated the optical forces generated within these structures, and compare the results with what is expected according to mathematical analysis wrote part of the manuscript, detailing the results and documenting the method used in the research. generated the plots used in the paper. collaborated with a remote supervisor in Florida, USA, while being based in St. Petersburg. presented the results of the publication at two conferences (poster and oral) in Russia.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Optical Fiber Skew Ray Tracing</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2015/04/17/skew-ray-tracing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Optical Fiber Skew Ray Tracing" />
      <published>2015-04-17T00:00:00+03:00</published>
      <updated>2015-04-17T00:00:00+03:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/research/2015/04/17/skew-ray-tracing</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2015/04/17/skew-ray-tracing/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wrote an introduction to Geometric Algebra - an esoteric form of vector mathematics well-suited for systems under rotation and with cylindrical symmetry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;created and polished the figures under the guidance of a co-author using &lt;strong&gt;AutoCAD 2010&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;performed the analytical calculations for ray tracing and obtained the expected results: the reflections of the light path as it travels along a cylindrical optical fiber traces a helix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;wrote the manuscript based on the process to obtain the results under the guidance of a co-author&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;showed that it is possible to trace the optical path without resorting to reducing methods normally shown in literature (simplifying the problem using only meridional/on-axis 2D rays on a plane or using computational methods/numerical simulations)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">wrote an introduction to Geometric Algebra - an esoteric form of vector mathematics well-suited for systems under rotation and with cylindrical symmetry created and polished the figures under the guidance of a co-author using AutoCAD 2010 performed the analytical calculations for ray tracing and obtained the expected results: the reflections of the light path as it travels along a cylindrical optical fiber traces a helix wrote the manuscript based on the process to obtain the results under the guidance of a co-author showed that it is possible to trace the optical path without resorting to reducing methods normally shown in literature (simplifying the problem using only meridional/on-axis 2D rays on a plane or using computational methods/numerical simulations)</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">BSc in Physics</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/education/2015/03/01/bs-physics/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="BSc in Physics" />
      <published>2015-03-01T00:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2015-03-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/education/2015/03/01/bs-physics</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/education/2015/03/01/bs-physics/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;official-university-description&quot;&gt;Official University description&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a 5-year program for students interested in acquiring the necessary knowledge and skills to do research in either theoretical or experimental physics. The aim is for students to gain a more in-depth familiarity with some of the most important concepts in physics and also develop skills in performing physics experiments. The program requires a submission and successful defense of a research thesis during the fifth year. The thesis can either be in theoretical or experimental physics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;notable-courses-taken&quot;&gt;Notable courses taken&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Computer-Aided Design (AutoCAD 2010)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engineering Workshop and Practices&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduction to Computing (instruction in C++ and C#)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduction to Data Structures (instruction in C++)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Classical Mechanics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Computational Physics (instruction in Fortran 90)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modern Topics in Materials Science and Engineering: Introduction to Nanotechnology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;organizations&quot;&gt;Organizations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2012-15: Ateneo League of Physicists&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2011-12: Ateneo Electronics and Computer Engineering Society, 2nd year Computer Engineering Batch Representative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2011-12: Ateneo Innovation Center&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="education" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Official University description</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title type="html">Gravitational orbits of the higher-order multipole moments</title>
      <link href="http://localhost:4000/research/2015/02/23/multipole-orbits/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gravitational orbits of the higher-order multipole moments" />
      <published>2015-02-23T00:00:00+02:00</published>
      <updated>2015-02-23T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
      <id>http://localhost:4000/research/2015/02/23/multipole-orbits</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/research/2015/02/23/multipole-orbits/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;studied the related works in literature about gravitational potentials, orbits, and numerical methods for solving differential equations. wrote the thesis text, summarized and drew conclusions from the results from the simulations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;adapted the code, in &lt;strong&gt;FORTRAN 90&lt;/strong&gt;, for the second-order Runge-Kutta method for solving the differential equation obtained from the orbit calculations, generated and post-processed roughly 10 billion datapoints&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;created the illustrations for the text in &lt;strong&gt;AutoCAD 2010&lt;/strong&gt;. plotted the numerical simulation results using &lt;strong&gt;gnuplot&lt;/strong&gt;, a command-line driven plotting utility for Linux systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;presented the results in front of a panel of four professors in the Physics Department&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      <author>
          <name></name>
        
        
      </author>

      
        <category term="research" />
      

      

      
        <summary type="html">studied the related works in literature about gravitational potentials, orbits, and numerical methods for solving differential equations. wrote the thesis text, summarized and drew conclusions from the results from the simulations adapted the code, in FORTRAN 90, for the second-order Runge-Kutta method for solving the differential equation obtained from the orbit calculations, generated and post-processed roughly 10 billion datapoints created the illustrations for the text in AutoCAD 2010. plotted the numerical simulation results using gnuplot, a command-line driven plotting utility for Linux systems presented the results in front of a panel of four professors in the Physics Department</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
</feed>
